<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-11T23:22:11+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Let’z Quiz!</title><subtitle>Challenge your knowledge and have fun while competing with your friends!</subtitle><author><name>Erik Pillon</name><email>quizmaster.lux@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Vengeance of the Quizmaster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/questions/the-vengeance-of-the-quizmaster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Vengeance of the Quizmaster" /><published>2024-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/questions/the-vengeance-of-the-quizmaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/questions/the-vengeance-of-the-quizmaster/"><![CDATA[<h2>General Knowledge</h2>
<ul>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> July 6th, 1885 is the anniversary of the first injection of the Rabies vaccine. Which famous scientist was responsible for this invention?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Louis Pasteur
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> During the celebrations of the last national day, Grand Duke Henry surprisingly announced that he started the abdication process of Luxembourg. Which one of his children will take the role of Grand Duke?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Guillame
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> In which German city was Karl Marx born?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Trier
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> The Luxembourgish Rene Arend, born in Wiltz in 1926, became famous the invention/creation of what?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Chicken McNuggets and McRib
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> If I am looking at the "Dancing House" (also called Ginger and Bread), in which city am I?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Prague, Novo Mesto
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Keith Richards is the guitarist of which band?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> The Rolling Stones
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which animal is the symbol of Madrid?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Bear
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> From which plant is tequila extracted?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Agave
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What's the name of the pioneering telescope that recently discovered the earliest and most distant galaxy ever observed?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> James Webb telescope
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Taylor Swift and the Swiftonomoics: how's called the current record braking Taylor Swift Tour?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Eras Tour
    </li>
  
</ul>

<h2>Books, TV Series and Boardgames </h2>
<ul>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> In the TV Series Friends, what is Ross shouting during the famous couch episode?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Pivot
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What's Sheldon Cooper middle name?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Lee
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Half a point for each of the siblings of Sherlock Holmes<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Mycroft and Enola
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> In which book (later adapted into a movie) can you find the sentence 'We accept the love we think we deserve'?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> The perks of being a wallflower
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which is the name of the first book of the Sherlock Holmes saga?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> A Study in Scarlet
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which Marvel character is known for breaking the fourth wall?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Deadpool
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which Bond villain famously had a third nipple?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Scaramanga, the man with the Golden Gun
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What's the name of the main character of Inside Out?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Riley
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which was the first weapon introduced in a Lego set?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Bow and Arrow
    </li>
  
</ul>

<h2>Sport</h2>
<ul>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Tour de France: Which British cyclist recently set the record for the biggest number of stage wins at Le Tour de France?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Mark Cavendish
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> One point for the starting and finishing city of the 2024 tour de France?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Florence, Nice
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which fruit can be found on top of the Wimbledon trophy?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Ananas. Strawberry is a good guess, but wrong
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which 2 countries hold the record for the biggest number of Euro Cup wins?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Germany and Spain, each with 3
    </li>
  
</ul>

<h2>Miscellaneous</h2>
<ul>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Paris 2024 will be which edition of the (summer) Olympic Games?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> 33th
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which is the only city that hosted the Olympic Games 3 times?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> London for a total of 4 (since 2024, also with Paris)
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> How's called the famous messenger that gave his life and from which the legend of the Marathon started?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Phydippides
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What is a Marathon's exact length (in meters)?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> 42195 meters, 26.2 miles
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Where will the 2024 Opening Ceremony be hosted?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Across the Seine
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which city will host the 2028 Olympic Games?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Los Angeles
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which country will go first during the Opening Ceremony Parade?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Greece
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What is the Pierre de Cubertin Medal? Please explain in max 5 words.<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Sportmanship medal during the Olympic Games
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> All the Olympic medals in Paris will have a piece of what?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Tour Eiffel
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> What's the only country that won medals (for a total of 10) only at the Winter Olympic Games?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Liechtenstein
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which element/technique is traditionally used to lit up the Olympic torch?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Sun, by means of parabolic mirrors
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> How many different countries hosted the Olympic Games?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> 19
    </li>
  
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Erik Pillon</name><email>quizmaster.lux@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Questions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun With Flags</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/questions/fun-with-flags/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun With Flags" /><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/questions/fun-with-flags</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/questions/fun-with-flags/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="erik-pillon-presents-fun-with-flags">Erik Pillon presents: Fun with Flags</h1>

<p>The following questions were asked during the special round “Erik Pillon presents: Fun with Flags” of the pubquiz on the 9th of September, 2022.</p>

<ul>
  
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> How many countries in the world have square flags?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Switzerland and Vatican City
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> There are only 3 countries in the world that have a dragon in their flag. Name one.<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Bhutan, Wales, Malta
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Only two countries have their map on their flag. Name one.<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Kosovo and Cyprus
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which National Flags display a Lion?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Bermuda, Jersey, Spain, Sri Lanka, and Luxembourg
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> It is normally a criminal offence to mutilate or burn the national flag. There’s only one reason why you can burn the US flag. Which is?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> It can’t be fixed or is dirty upon cleaning
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> The flag of Paraguay has the unique feature of what?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> 
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which is the most common color on national flags?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Red, 105 flags. Red symbolizes bravery and sufferance, blue Sky-Ocean but also Peace and freedom, Black: self-determinism ethnic heritage
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> How many colors are there in the South African Flag?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Six: Black, Yellow, Green, White, Black, Red, Blue
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which country has the oldest flag?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> first used in 1925, the design goes back to 1219
    </li>
  
    <li>
      <strong>Question:</strong> Which is the only flag in the world that doesn’t have 4 edges?<br />
      <strong>Answer:</strong> Nepal
    </li>
  
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Erik Pillon</name><email>quizmaster.lux@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Questions" /><category term="fun-with-flags" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Erik Pillon presents: Fun with Flags]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Letz Quiz!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/letz-quiz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Letz Quiz!" /><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/letz-quiz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/letz-quiz/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcome">Welcome</h1>

<p><strong>Hello world</strong>, this is my first blog post.</p>

<p>I hope you like it!</p>]]></content><author><name>Erik Pillon</name><email>quizmaster.lux@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Posts" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></summary></entry></feed>